Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we're talking about American education and college life.
我是Catherine，今天我们聊聊美国教育和大学生活。
That's right.
没错。
This is actually a user suggestion that they wanted to know more or less what it would
这其实是用户建议的，他们想大致了解
be like a dialogue between friends on a typical day in college.
朋友之间在大学典型一天里的对话是什么样的。
Alright so this is an advanced level lesson.
好的，这是一节高级课程。
We're going to be talking in a normal conversational speed.
我们会以正常的对话速度来交流。
We're going to listen to the dialogue and when we come back we'll talk about some of
我们先听对话，回来后再讨论一些
these key phrases and words that might help you understand the dialogue better.
可能帮助你更好理解对话的关键短语和词汇。
Hey Jordan, is that you?
嘿，Jordan，是你吗？
Long time no see.
好久不见。
Oh hey, no kidding.
哦，嘿，可不是嘛。
I haven't seen you since orientation three months ago.
自从三个月前的迎新会之后就没见过你了。
So how you been?
你过得怎么样？
Settling into college life okay?
适应大学生活了吗？
Yeah, I think so.
嗯，我觉得还行。
I pledged Phi Iota Alpha so I'm living at the frat house now.
我加入了Phi Iota Alpha兄弟会，现在住在兄弟会房子里。
Oh, so you're a frat boy now, huh?
哦，所以你现在是个兄弟会男孩了，哈？
Yeah, yeah, I know.
是啊，是啊，我知道。
That's totally cliche, but really I think it's been a good decision.
这确实很老套，但我真的觉得这是个好决定。
Got a lot of support and good suggestions from the guys.
从兄弟们那里得到了很多支持和好建议。
What about you?
你呢？
What have you been up to?
你最近在忙什么？
Well, not much.
嗯，没什么特别的。
I'm still living at home and commuting to school.
我还住在家里，通勤上学。
I ended up dropping that metalworking class I was so excited about.
我最终退掉了那门我原本很兴奋的金属加工课。
It just wasn't as interesting as I'd hoped.
它没有我想象的那么有趣。
The guidance counselor suggested that I focus on my prerequisite courses so that I can make
指导顾问建议我专注于先修课程，这样能确保
sure the credits count.
学分有效。
That sounds smart, but kind of boring.
听起来挺明智的，但有点无聊。
Yeah, it is a little bit.
是啊，是有点。
I joined the Great Outdoors Club though, which has been a lot of fun.
不过我加入了“大户外俱乐部”，挺有意思的。
We've gone on two camping trips already and I've made some good friends.
我们已经去了两次露营旅行，还交了一些好朋友。
That's cool.
真酷。
Hey, so have you decided on your major yet?
嘿，那你决定专业了吗？
Definitely pre-med.
肯定是医学预科。
What about you?
你呢？
I still have no clue, but we don't have to declare a major until our sophomore year,
我还是没头绪，但我们到大二才需要确定专业，
so I've got time.
所以我有时间。
Oops, I'm late for class.
哎呀，我上课要迟到了。
I've got to run.
我得赶紧走了。
Okay, take care.
好的，保重。
Hey, nice running into you.
嘿，很高兴碰到你。
Yeah, you too.
嗯，你也是。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's start with all these words and phrases on Language Takeaway.
现在开始看“语言要点”里的这些词汇和短语。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
So hey Jordan, is that you?
所以，嘿，Jordan，是你吗？
Long time no see.
好久不见。
I love this phrase.
我喜欢这个短语。
Right, this phrase, long time no see, which if you look at it, it doesn't really make
对，这个短语“long time no see”，如果你看它，其实不太
sense.
合理。
It looks like we're missing a couple of words.
看起来我们少了一些词。
It looks like an incomplete sentence.
看起来像个不完整的句子。
Yeah, like the subject, who?
是啊，比如主语，谁？
Right.
对。
I haven't seen you, you haven't seen you.
我没见过你，你没见过你。
So really the meaning of this is I haven't seen you in a long time.
所以它的意思其实是“我很久没见你了”。
That's right.
没错。
And actually I've heard that this phrase was taken from Chinese.
而且我听说这个短语是从中文来的。
I've also heard that, so it's kind of like pigeon English.
我也听说过，所以它有点像洋泾浜英语。
And now it's very, very common in English to say this.
现在在英语里说这个非常非常常见。
You say this with your friends.
你和朋友之间会说这个。
It's very casual.
它很随意。
And yeah, long time no see.
嗯，是的，好久不见。
Because if you translate this literally to Chinese, it makes sense, right?
因为如果你把它直译成中文，它是有意义的，对吧？
Yes, it does.
是的，没错。
So it's interesting.
所以挺有意思的。
All right, so we haven't seen our friend in a long time.
好的，所以我们很久没见我们的朋友了。
And he's like, yeah, no kidding.
他说，是啊，可不是嘛。
You know what?
你知道吗？
I think it's been since orientation.
我觉得自从迎新会之后就没见过了。
So what is this orientation that he's talking about?
那他说的“orientation”是什么？
Now this is an important part of the average American college experience.
这是普通美国大学经历中的一个重要部分。
Orientation is a special time, maybe for one week or a couple of days, at the very beginning
迎新会是一个特殊的时间，可能是一周或几天，在
of your first year of university.
你大学第一年的最开始。
All right, so my first week of school, I didn't have any classes, but I went to school and
好的，所以我上学的第一周，我没有课，但我去了学校，
with all of the other first year students, we're called freshmen, I had to do activities
和其他所有一年级学生（我们叫新生）一起，我参加了活动，
and meet people and sign up for classes.
见了人，还选了课。
And basically, orientation is a time when you learn about a new system or a new program.
基本上，迎新会就是让你了解一个新系统或新项目的时候。
So how it works, because maybe you don't really know yet how to pick your classes or where
它的运作方式是，因为你可能还不知道怎么选课、宿舍在哪里，
the dorms are or how the meals work if you have to go to the cafeteria, etc., right?
或者如果要去食堂吃饭的话，用餐流程是怎样的，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
And it comes from the verb to orient.
这个词来自动词“orient”。
So I orient myself by facing the right direction.
所以我通过面向正确的方向来定位自己。
So orientation is really about teaching you how to start in a new system.
所以迎新会实际上是教你如何在一个新系统中开始。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So well, that was three months ago and a lot has happened.
嗯，那是三个月前的事了，现在发生了很多变化。
Our speaker says that he pledged Phi Iota Alpha.
我们的说话者说他加入了Phi Iota Alpha兄弟会。
So what is this to pledge in this?
那么这里的“pledge”是什么意思呢？
Now this is Greek as well.
这也是希腊字母。
Phi Iota Alpha is Greek and this means that we're talking about a fraternity.
Phi Iota Alpha是希腊字母，这意味着我们在谈论一个兄弟会。
So fraternity is a group of boys, a sorority is a group of girls, and these are communities,
所以兄弟会是一群男生，姐妹会是一群女生，这些是社区，
so social societies that you have to apply to be a member of.
也就是你需要申请才能成为会员的社交团体。
But we don't say apply.
但我们不说“申请”。
Right, you pledge.
对，你说“pledge”。
So it's like I pledge allegiance.
就像我说“我宣誓效忠”一样。
You say I want to be in your group, I want to be in your fraternity, and so you will
你说我想加入你的团体，我想加入你的兄弟会，所以你需要
have to do special things to become a member.
做一些特别的事情才能成为会员。
So the verb to pledge would be to basically to promise something honorably or faithfully,
所以动词“pledge”基本上就是光荣地或忠诚地承诺某事，
right?
对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
And that's the nice way of putting it.
这是一种好听的说法。
But generally when you talk about sororities and fraternities, these upperclassmen, so
但通常当你谈论姐妹会和兄弟会时，这些高年级学生，也就是
third, fourth year students, they make the students who are pledging do very weird things.
大三、大四的学生，会让正在宣誓入会的新生做一些非常奇怪的事情。
So as you said, this is for these two guys, this is for a fraternity.
所以就像你说的，对这两个人来说，这是针对兄弟会的。
But if it's this type of club for girls, it's called a?
但如果这是女生的俱乐部，它叫什么呢？
Sorority.
姐妹会。
Okay, so it's different.
好的，所以不一样。
So I'm pledging this sorority, that means I'm trying to become a member of this sorority.
所以我说“我在加入这个姐妹会”，意思是我在努力成为这个姐妹会的成员。
So I think it's worthwhile mentioning many of you have probably seen it in movies, these
所以我觉得值得提一下，你们很多人可能在电影里见过这些
fraternities or sororities, and they all have names based on the Greek alphabet.
兄弟会或姐妹会，它们都有基于希腊字母的名字。
Right, so the letters, Phi, Iota, Alpha, or Kappa, Kappa, Gamma, these are the letters
对，所以字母Phi、Iota、Alpha，或者Kappa、Kappa、Gamma，这些字母
that basically represent the name of the fraternity.
基本上代表了兄弟会的名字。
And what's interesting is that maybe I am in Kappa Kappa Gamma at my school, there's
有趣的是，也许我在我的学校是Kappa Kappa Gamma的成员，另一所学校
another school with another Kappa Kappa Gamma, we're all related.
也有另一个Kappa Kappa Gamma，我们都有联系。
It's the same social community.
这是同一个社交团体。
So they sometimes do events together, things like that.
所以他们有时会一起举办活动之类的。
So actually these fraternities or sororities, it's not independent to a school, it's actually
所以实际上这些兄弟会或姐妹会并不独立于学校，它实际上是
like a wide network of people that belong to this club.
一个广泛的网络，属于这个俱乐部的人。
Exactly, it's a national network usually.
没错，通常是一个全国性的网络。
So it's kind of like being in the Boy Scouts.
所以有点像加入童子军。
Yeah, similar except the activities are much different.
是的，类似，只是活动内容大不相同。
That's right.
没错。
So these people, they may live at the frat house, like in this dialogue, he's living
所以这些人可能住在兄弟会房子里，就像这段对话里，他住在
at the frat house.
兄弟会房子里。
Now remember here, fraternity, that becomes frat if we're talking colloquially.
现在记住，fraternity，如果口语化地说，就变成frat。
So the frat house is the fraternity house, it's where those boys live, but only the Phi,
所以frat house就是兄弟会房子，是那些男生住的地方，但只有Phi、
Iota, Alpha boys.
Iota、Alpha的男生。
Right, so no one, if I have a friend and he's not Phi, Iota, Alpha, then he can't live there.
对，所以如果我有朋友不是Phi、Iota、Alpha的，他就不能住那里。
Exactly, and we have a similar thing for girls, that's the sorority house.
没错，女生也有类似的东西，那就是姐妹会房子。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So a frat house is the fraternity house, basically like their club house.
所以frat house就是兄弟会房子，基本上就是他们的俱乐部会所。
Where they live though, yeah.
不过他们住在那里，是的。
And so sometimes guys that belong to fraternities, they're referred to as frat boys.
所以有时属于兄弟会的男生被称为frat boys。
Hey, frat boy, yeah, so fraternity boy, this is not always the nicest thing to say, it's
嘿，frat boy，是的，就是兄弟会男生，这不一定是个好听的称呼，它
got a negative meaning, because a lot of the activities that frat boys do stereotypically
带有负面含义，因为刻板印象中frat boys的很多活动
involve lots of drinking and maybe being loud.
都涉及大量饮酒和吵闹。
So frat boy is someone who's in a fraternity and it's usually a critical way of talking
所以frat boy是指兄弟会里的成员，通常是一种批评性的说法
about those guys.
来谈论这些男生。
So this whole fraternity, sorority thing, as he said, is a little bit cliche, right?
所以整个兄弟会、姐妹会的事情，就像他说的，有点老套，对吧？
Yeah, this is a great word, I use this a lot actually.
是的，这是个好词，我其实经常用。
So something that's cliche would be almost what's expected, but in a bad way, right?
所以老套的东西几乎就是意料之中的，但带有负面意味，对吧？
And so...
所以...
So you joining a fraternity is a little bit cliche, because it's kind of like...
所以你加入兄弟会有点老套，因为这有点像...
It's what everyone does in the movies and on TV, like, oh, I'm going to college, I'm
电影和电视里每个人都这么做，比如，“哦，我要上大学了，我要
going to join a fraternity.
加入一个兄弟会。”
It's almost like boring, it's so normal.
这几乎有点无聊，太普通了。
But you could also say that like that movie, at the end of the movie, the man and the woman,
但你也可以说，比如那部电影，结尾时，男人和女人，
they fought, but then they got back together, it's so cliche.
他们吵过架，但又和好了，这太老套了。
So it's something that's overused, expected, very typical.
所以这是被过度使用、意料之中、非常典型的东西。
Uninteresting.
无趣。
Uninteresting, okay.
无趣，好的。
So we have a cliche, we're saying that a fraternity is cliche.
所以我们有“老套”这个词，我们在说兄弟会老套。
Now, the other guy on the other hand is living off campus, he lives at home, but he said
现在，另一个人则住在校外，他住在家里，但他说
he commutes to school every day.
他每天通勤去学校。
So he says, I'm commuting to school.
所以他说，“我每天通勤去学校。”
This is interesting.
这很有趣。
Now in America, there's usually two options.
在美国，通常有两种选择。
One is to live on campus, that means to live at your university in a dormitory or an apartment.
一种选择是住在校园里，也就是住在大学的宿舍或公寓里。
But many people commute, and this means they drive to school every day, and then they drive
但很多人通勤，这意味着他们每天开车去学校，然后晚上再开车
home at night, they don't live on the campus.
回家，他们不住在校园里。
So you can also commute to work every day, right?
所以你也可以每天通勤上班，对吧？
This is what people do, you don't live at the office.
这就是人们常做的事，你不住在办公室。
Exactly.
没错。
I hope not.
我希望不是。
No, this is a common thing, people will drive to work, and you might ask them, how long
不，这是很常见的事，人们会开车去上班，你可能会问他们，
is your commute?
你的通勤时间有多长？
So you say, oh, one hour, that means I drive one hour to work.
所以你会说，哦，一个小时，意思是我开车一小时去上班。
So if I take the bus or the train, the subway, is that also commuting?
那么如果我坐公交车、火车或地铁，这也算通勤吗？
It is, it doesn't matter how you do it, it just means you don't live where you work or
算的，不管你用什么方式，它只是意味着你不住在工作或学习的地方，
where you study, so you have to travel there by some means of transportation.
所以你必须通过某种交通工具去那里。
Okay.
好的。
So, well, now going back to the academic aspect of this dialogue, he said that he ended up
那么，现在我们回到这段对话的学术方面，他说他最终
dropping a class.
退了一门课。
Okay, so to drop means to stop attending a class.
好的，所以“drop”意思是停止上一门课。
Maybe you don't have enough time, maybe you don't like it, but to drop a class means you
也许你没有足够的时间，也许你不喜欢它，但退课意味着你
will no longer study, you will not take the tests, you will not get a grade.
不再学习，不会参加考试，也不会得到成绩。
It's the opposite of to sign up for a class or to register for a class.
这与报名上课或注册课程相反。
So the difference between dropping a class and failing a class is that basically you're
所以退课和挂科的区别在于，基本上是你
making the decision to not go there anymore.
自己决定不再去上课了。
Exactly.
没错。
So usually there's a time you can do this, so for the first two weeks you can attend
所以通常有一个时间窗口可以这样做，比如前两周你可以去
classes and if you don't have enough time or you don't like a class, you can drop the
上课，如果你没有足够的时间或不喜欢某门课，你可以退掉
class.
那门课。
But if you stay in the class, you just don't come or you do very poorly on your tests,
但如果你继续上这门课，只是不去上课或考试考得很差，
that's called failing.
那就叫挂科。
So there are some classes, because I don't know, can you drop any class or do you have
那么有些课程，因为我不知道，是不是任何课都能退，还是说
to take them at some point?
你必须在某个时候修完它们？
That's a good question.
这是个好问题。
That's our next phrase, that's a prerequisite course, right?
这就是我们下一个短语，那是先修课程，对吧？
So usually the university in America will tell you, you have to study math, you have
所以通常美国的大学会告诉你，你必须学数学，你必须
to study one semester of science, you have to study English for one semester.
学一个学期的科学，你必须学一个学期的英语。
So these are called prerequisites.
这些就叫做先修课程。
It's when the university tells you, you have to study something.
就是大学告诉你必须学某些东西。
And I think you also have some courses that you can't take until you've passed some other
而且我认为还有一些课程，你必须先通过其他课程才能上，
course, right?
对吧？
So for example, you can't take economy unless you've passed calculus.
比如，除非你通过了微积分，否则不能上经济学。
Exactly.
没错。
So that's another prerequisite.
所以那是另一种先修课程。
So we'd say, the prerequisite for economics is calculus one.
所以我们会说，经济学的先修课程是微积分一。
Or the prerequisite for Spanish 200 is Spanish 100.
或者西班牙语200的先修课程是西班牙语100。
Means you have to take something before you take something else.
意思是你必须先学某样东西，才能学另一样东西。
So there's two meanings of the word, but they're both related to requirements, what you have
所以这个词有两种含义，但它们都与要求有关，也就是你
to do.
必须做的事。
Okay, you need a requirement.
好的，你需要一个要求。
Now moving on and talking about the major, he said, well, if you decided on a major and
现在继续谈专业，他说，嗯，如果你决定了专业，然后
he said, well, pre-med.
他说，嗯，医学预科。
All right, so major, first of all, is what you choose to study, right?
好的，所以“major”首先是你选择学习的领域，对吧？
The focus of your study.
你学习的重点。
Exactly, the focus.
没错，重点。
You might study other classes, but your focus, your main interest area is one thing.
你可能还上其他课，但你的重点、主要兴趣领域是一个方向。
And in his case, he's talking about pre-med.
在他的情况下，他谈的是医学预科。
Now what does pre-med stand for?
那么“pre-med”代表什么？
Because it is a short version of a longer word.
因为它是一个较长单词的缩写。
So it's pre-medicine.
所以它是“pre-medicine”。
Yeah, okay.
是的，好的。
So medicine is something you study if you want to be a doctor.
所以医学是你如果想当医生就要学的东西。
Because in America, you don't become a doctor after four years.
因为在美国，你不能在四年后就成为医生。
You have to go get your BA, your bachelor's degree, and then you have to get your PhD,
你必须先拿到学士学位，然后还要拿到博士学位。
your doctorate.
你的博士学位。
So people who want to go to graduate school first have to study many required courses.
所以想上研究生院的人必须先学很多必修课程。
That's the pre-med focus.
这就是医学预科的重点。
Okay, so that's what he's talking about.
好的，所以这就是他谈的内容。
He's definitely going to focus on pre-med.
他肯定会专注于医学预科。
He wants to be a doctor.
他想当医生。
He's not going to be a doctor soon, but he wants to start studying to be a doctor.
他不会很快成为医生，但他想开始学习成为医生。
So he will become a pre-med, a pre-med major.
所以他会成为医学预科生，一个医学预科专业的学生。
And what about for lawyers?
那律师呢？
I know that there are also something that you focus on before.
我知道也有一个你之前要专注的领域。
There is, yeah.
有的，是的。
That's called pre-law.
那叫法律预科。
Same idea.
同样的概念。
Pre means before.
“Pre”意思是之前。
So obviously, a lawyer needs to study for a long time as well.
所以显然，律师也需要学习很长时间。
And with your undergrad degree, so your first four years, you would study pre-law.
在你的本科学位期间，也就是前四年，你会学习法律预科。
So this is what you focus on for your four years, and then you go into grad school and
所以这是你四年专注的内容，然后你进入研究生院，
become an attorney or a specific type of lawyer.
成为律师或特定类型的法律从业者。
But a lawyer doesn't have to study for a PhD.
但律师不需要攻读博士学位。
A lawyer studies for a JD.
律师攻读的是法学博士学位。
That's called a Juris Doctorate.
那叫做法学博士。
That's the law degree.
那是法律学位。
Interesting.
有意思。
Okay.
好的。
So, well, he's going into pre-med, but the other guy is like, well, I don't have a clue
所以，嗯，他打算读医学预科，但另一个人呢，就像，嗯，我还没什么头绪。
yet.
还没。
And he doesn't have to declare a major until the sophomore year.
而且他直到大二才需要确定专业。
Okay, a couple of things going on here.
好的，这里有几件事要讲。
First of all, there are different names for each year.
首先，每个年级都有不同的名称。
So freshmen, sophomore, junior, senior.
所以是大一、大二、大三、大四。
One, two, three, four.
一、二、三、四。
So sophomore year is the second year.
所以大二就是第二年。
So if you say I'm a sophomore student at XY University, that means you're in your second
所以如果你说我是XY大学的大二学生，那就意味着你是在第二
year.
年。
Exactly.
没错。
And he says that he doesn't have to declare a major until his second year, until his sophomore
他说他直到第二年，也就是大二，才需要确定专业。
year.
年。
And this phrase, to declare a major, is very important.
而“确定专业”这个短语非常重要。
It means that you will tell the university what your focus will be.
它的意思是你会告诉大学你的学习重点是什么。
Right.
对。
And you have to do this.
而且你必须这么做。
You can't just go to school and then graduate.
你不能只是去上学然后毕业。
You have to say, I will focus on this because every major has what we just talked about,
你必须说，我会专注于这个，因为每个专业都有我们刚才提到的，
prerequisites.
先修课程。
Right.
对。
So, but in this first year, you don't have to tell the university yet what you want to
所以，但在第一年，你还不必告诉大学你想
study.
学什么。
Maybe you just, you take a variety of courses and then you tell them, okay, now I'm going
也许你只是，你上各种课程，然后你告诉他们，好了，现在我要
to focus on this.
专注于这个了。
Right.
对。
Exactly.
没错。
That's what I did.
我就是这么做的。
And that's very common for liberal art schools.
这在文理学院很常见。
Maybe if you're in a specific trade school or you're in a certain track, you would have
也许如果你在特定的职业学校或特定的轨道上，你会有
a different situation.
不同的情况。
But for me, liberal arts, I studied history, I studied philosophy, I studied language and
但对我来说，文理学院，我学过历史、哲学、语言和
literature.
文学。
And then my sophomore year, my second year, I decided, oh, I will study philosophy.
然后到了大二，我的第二年，我决定，哦，我要学哲学。
And that's.
然后就是。
So you're going to focus on that.
所以你要专注于那个。
Yes.
是的。
One thing.
有一点。
So it's, it's interesting because, uh, in many other countries, the education system
所以这很有趣，因为，嗯，在很多其他国家，教育系统
requires you to declare your major before you start studying, right?
要求你在开始学习之前就确定专业，对吧？
You say, well, I'm going to study business.
你说，嗯，我要学商科。
And then your, your four years are around that.
然后你的，你的四年都围绕这个。
Whereas in some, in some places in the United States or for some majors, you don't have
而在美国的一些地方或对于一些专业，你不必
to do that.
这么做。
That's true.
没错。
In England, for example, you have one area of study, one major, and that's all you study,
例如在英国，你只有一个学习领域，一个专业，而且你只学那个，
right?
对吧？
Because in, in, in the U S you can get a major in history with a minor in philosophy, right?
因为在美国，你可以主修历史并辅修哲学，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
I was the opposite.
我正好相反。
I had a major in philosophy and a minor in history.
我主修哲学，辅修历史。
So major means something bigger, more important and minor is smaller or less important.
所以主修意味着更大、更重要，辅修则更小或次要。
And a minor is, uh, is your second field of study.
而辅修是，嗯，是你的第二学习领域。
So you take fewer classes, but you still know something about that.
所以你上的课更少，但你对那个领域还是有所了解。
But do they always have to be related because like, for example, can you be a major of philosophy
但它们必须相关吗？因为比如，你能主修哲学并
with a minor in, I don't know, astronomy or something like that?
辅修，我不知道，天文学之类的吗？
Absolutely.
当然可以。
Something like pre-med.
比如医学预科。
So medicine, it's hard because there's so many requirements, right?
所以医学，这很难，因为要求很多，对吧？
But I had a number of friends who are major in computer science and a minor in, um, literature,
但我有很多朋友主修计算机科学，并辅修，嗯，文学，
for example.
比如。
So you can, you can mix it up at certain schools.
所以在某些学校，你可以混合搭配。
So what would be the advantage of that, uh, of doing something like that?
那么这样做有什么好处呢，嗯，做类似的事情？
You know, because most places or most education systems say that you or teach that, you know,
你知道，因为大多数地方或大多数教育系统都说或教导你，你知道，
you should specialize, you should be focused on one area.
你应该专精，你应该专注于一个领域。
So if you're in computer science, then you should be focused on that.
所以如果你学计算机科学，那么你应该专注于那个。
So why, why would somebody specialize in computer science in their major, but then take a minor
那为什么有人会主修计算机科学，但又辅修
in like literature or something?
像文学之类的呢？
Well, let's use that example.
嗯，就用那个例子吧。
I think one of the benefits for the liberal arts degree, and this is something they talk
我认为文理学位的一个好处，这也是他们在教育中经常
about a lot in education, is that you have a broad area of knowledge.
讨论的，是你有广泛的知识面。
So yes, you know a lot about computer science.
所以是的，你对计算机科学了解很多。
You have to, to graduate, but maybe in your future you will write articles about computer
你必须这样，才能毕业，但也许将来你会写关于计算机科学的文章，
science or you want a blog or you want a job that has a public relations aspect.
或者你想开博客，或者你想要一份涉及公关的工作。
You need to know how to write, and you're not going to learn how to write in all of
你需要知道如何写作，而你在所有
your computer science classes, but you will by reading a lot and writing a lot in your
你的计算机科学课程，但你会通过大量阅读和写作来学习
literature classes.
文学课。
So some people like to say that it's very good to mix up business and languages or computer
所以有些人喜欢说，把商业和语言或计算机科学混在一起很好
science and literature because it's a way to be well-rounded.
科学与文学，因为这是全面发展的方式。
That's right.
没错。
That's actually interesting because in most places, specifically in the exact sciences
这其实很有趣，因为在大多数地方，特别是在精确科学领域
fields, they focus more on that, like engineers.
他们更注重这些，比如工程师。
It's all about engineering, math, and all this, but the human aspect, like you said,
全是工程、数学之类的，但人文方面，就像你说的，
or the liberal arts aspect, like literature or history, they don't get much of that.
或者文科方面，比如文学或历史，他们接触得不多。
So when you actually have to become a manager or write or manage people, you don't really
所以当你真的需要成为经理或写作或管理人时，你并不真正
have the skills to do that because you never really took a class.
有技能去做，因为你从未上过这类课。
That's right, and it can be very hard to learn how to write well and to speak well all of
没错，而且突然学会写好和说好可能非常困难
a sudden.
一下子。
Right, right.
对，对。
And I think that's where people struggle also when they're applying for jobs.
我认为这也是人们在申请工作时挣扎的地方。
So I don't know.
所以我不知道。
I believe in being a well-rounded individual.
我相信做一个全面发展的人。
Obviously there's some benefits to being very, very knowledgeable about one thing.
显然，对一件事非常非常精通有一些好处。
So I guess we could ask you guys, our users, do you believe that it's better to be knowledgeable
所以我想我们可以问问你们，我们的用户，你们认为精通一件事更好
about one thing or maybe more well-rounded and to be an expert in many different things?
还是更全面发展，成为许多不同领域的专家？
That's right.
没错。
Yeah, you should let us know.
是的，你应该告诉我们。
Let's jump into our dialogue one last time.
让我们最后一次进入我们的对话。
Let's take a look at what everyone was saying and we'll be back in a bit.
让我们看看大家说了什么，我们一会儿回来。
Hey, Jordan, is that you?
嘿，乔丹，是你吗？
Long time no see.
好久不见。
Oh, hey, no kidding.
哦，嘿，可不是嘛。
I haven't seen you since orientation three months ago.
自从三个月前的迎新会我就没见过你了。
So how you been?
你过得怎么样？
Settling into college life okay?
适应大学生活了吗？
Yeah, I think so.
是的，我想是的。
I pledged Phi Iota Alpha, so I'm living at the frat house now.
我加入了Phi Iota Alpha兄弟会，所以现在住在兄弟会房子里。
Oh, so you're a frat boy now, huh?
哦，所以你现在是个兄弟会男孩了，嗯？
Yeah, yeah, I know.
是啊，是啊，我知道。
It's totally cliche, but really I think it's been a good decision.
这完全是老套，但我真的觉得这是个好决定。
Got a lot of support and good suggestions from the guys.
从兄弟们那里得到了很多支持和好建议。
What about you?
你呢？
What have you been up to?
你最近在忙什么？
Well, not much.
嗯，没什么。
I'm still living at home and commuting to school.
我还住在家里，通勤上学。
I ended up dropping that metalworking class I was so excited about.
我最终退掉了那个我本来很兴奋的金属加工课。
It just wasn't as interesting as I'd hoped.
它没有我想象的那么有趣。
The guidance counselor suggested that I focus on my prerequisite courses so that I can make
指导顾问建议我专注于先修课程，这样我就能确保
sure the credits count.
学分算数。
That sounds smart, but kind of boring.
听起来很聪明，但有点无聊。
Yeah, it is a little bit.
是啊，是有点。
I joined the Great Outdoors Club, though, which has been a lot of fun.
不过我加入了户外俱乐部，这很有趣。
We've gone on two camping trips already and I've made some good friends.
我们已经去了两次露营旅行，交了一些好朋友。
That's cool.
真酷。
Hey, so have you decided on your major yet?
嘿，你决定专业了吗？
Definitely pre-med.
肯定是医学预科。
What about you?
你呢？
I still have no clue, but we don't have to declare a major until our sophomore year,
我还是没头绪，但我们直到大二才需要申报专业，
so I've got time.
所以我还有时间。
Oops, I'm late for class.
哎呀，我上课要迟到了。
I've got to run.
我得赶紧走了。
Okay, take care.
好的，保重。
Hey, nice running into you.
嘿，很高兴碰到你。
Yeah, you too.
是啊，你也是。
Alright, so it's a very interesting topic.
好了，这是个非常有趣的话题。
Education systems are so different around the world.
世界各地的教育系统差异很大。
The way that you go to college, how many years.
你上大学的方式，多少年。
I know that in England you can do a master's in a year, I think.
我知道在英国，你可以在一年内完成硕士学位，我想。
One year.
一年。
Whereas in the States it's two.
而在美国是两年。
Or three.
或者三年。
I think even a bachelor's in England is three years.
我想在英国，学士学位也是三年。
I believe so, yeah.
我相信是的。
But they also have an extra year of high school.
但他们还有额外一年的高中。
An extra year of high school.
额外一年的高中。
Fifth year, yeah.
第五年，是的。
Oh, okay.
哦，好的。
So every system is a bit different.
所以每个系统都有点不同。
In America, generally, it's either two or four years for your college degree.
在美国，通常大学学位是两年或四年。
And then, yeah, it's graduate school for two, three, or four years.
然后，是的，研究生院是两、三或四年。
Now one of the interesting things that I found is kind of unique to the Latin American education
我发现的一个有趣的事情是，拉丁美洲教育系统有点独特
system is that people can actually go to college for five years for majors like in business.
人们实际上可以上大学五年，比如商业专业。
And what they do is they call it a commercial engineer.
他们称之为商业工程师。
So it's like an engineering major, but it's not really engineering because it's business.
所以它像工程专业，但又不是真正的工程，因为是商业。
So it's interesting because you go to school for five years to be a business major.
所以很有趣，因为你上五年学来成为商业专业的学生。
Interesting.
有意思。
Well, we have something called a joint program, J-O-I-N-T, joint meaning coming together.
嗯，我们有一种叫联合课程的东西，J-O-I-N-T，joint 意思是“联合在一起”。
And you could do that.
你可以这样做。
You could be, for example, a chemistry major, but also a business major.
比如，你可以主修化学，同时也可以主修商科。
And then maybe go into oil refinery or some kind of very specialized business where you
然后也许进入炼油厂或某种非常专业的行业，在那里
do need to know something about chemistry.
你确实需要懂一些化学知识。
And that's called a joint degree.
这就叫做联合学位。
That's really smart as well.
那也很聪明。
Yeah, I think so.
是啊，我也这么觉得。
Well, it's interesting.
嗯，这挺有意思的。
Let us know what you studied.
告诉我们你学的是什么。
Maybe you went to school for two years.
也许你只上了两年学。
I think you can get a technical degree in two years?
我觉得两年可以拿到一个技术学位吧？
Yeah, associate's degree or a technical degree for two years.
是的，两年可以拿到副学士学位或技术学位。
And then you can get a bachelor's, a master's, a PhD.
然后你可以拿到学士、硕士、博士学位。
Let us know what your education background is like and how it works in your country.
告诉我们你的教育背景是什么样的，以及你们国家的情况是怎样的。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是 EnglishPod.com。
We hope to see you there.
我们希望能在那里见到你。
All right, guys.
好了，各位。
Bye.
再见。
All right.
好的。